Guide to the Grace A. Kempton and Willet Main Kempton Family Papers M2004
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Grace A. Kempton and Willet M. Kempton family papers
1937-1978
bulk
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Kempton, Grace Arrington
Kempton, Willett Main
M2004
17 Linear Feet (46 boxes, 1 map folder)
Correspondence and printed material largely related to World War II from the papers of Grace Kempton, who worked for the Army Public Relations Office and later joined the Women's Army Corp (WAC), and her husband Willett Kempton, who worked for the Office of War Information (OWI).
Acquisition Information
Gift of John Houston Kempton. Accession 2014-016.
Access to Collection
The materials are open for research use.
Scope and Contents
The Kempton Family Collection contains correspondence and printed material relating to World War II from Grace Arrington Kempton and her husband Willett Main Kempton, both of whom were journalists involved with morale and propaganda efforts.
Willet Kempton was Grace's journalism instructor at the University of Georgia. They were married in 1939 and Grace Kempton began writing a column for Southern newspapers. In 1942 she started working with the Army Public Relations Office. The following year, Grace enlisted in the Women's Army Corps, working in the Pentagon for the Bureau of Public Relations’ Morale Services. There she managed information about the WACs and published articles in magazines such as Yank and Overseas Woman.
During the war, Willet Kempton was Department Director of Information for the Office for Emergency Management, which later transitioned to the Office of War Information. Willet wrote the syndicated “Home Front” and” Answers to Your War Questions” columns, as well as tracking and reviewing other war news. In 1943 he was in charge of radio relations for the agency. In this capacity, Kempton was involved with the United Nations conference in San Francisco in 1945. He later taught at American University, eventually becoming chair of the Department of Communications.
The collection contains correspondence, memoranda, notes, typescripts, press releases and drafts of articles, as well as many newspapers and clippings, including camp newsletters and other publications with limited distribution.
There are also related materials from family members Judson Kempton (who served as a medic in England in the late 1930s) and Homer Arrington (who served as a navigator in the Air Force in Europe during World War Two). Also included is a genealogy chart prepared by John Houston Kempton (son of Willett and Grace Kempton).
Biographical / Historical
Grace Arrington Kempton
Grace Arrington was born in Rome, Georgia in 1916. She earned an A.B. in English literature from Shorter College, then a B.A. in journalism from the University of Georgia in 1940. She married one of her journalism instructors, Willett Main Kempton, on August 5, 1939. Her journalism career began as a society columnist for the Banner Herald in Athens, GA in 1940, and she was later a reporter for the Atlanta Constitution (1942) and the Army Public Relations Office (1942­1943) before writing society columns for Palm Beach (FL) Life (1947) and the McLean Providence Journal (1952­1953). Grace enlisted in the army in 1943, and served in the Women's Army Corps at the Pentagon during World War II, where she attained the rank of captain before departing in 1945. She was ever active in her community, and was a member of the Women's Board of the George Washington University Hospital (1953), the Northern VA board of Realtors, the VA Real Estate Association, the American Newspaper Women's Club, the National Trust for Historic Preservation, Chi Omega, Women in Communications, the Heritage Foundation, and the Capital Speakers Club. Grace served as publicity chairman of the Fairfax County Cancer Society (1953), director of the McLean Horse Show Association, and in 1975, President of the Georgia State Society. She founded and ran a public relations firm, the "Embassy Service Bureau" (1946 – 1947), then served as an administrative assistant to congressman Henderson Lanham (GA) from 1947 – 1948. She founded in 1955 the Grace A. Kempton Realty Company in Mclean, which she ran until the late 1980's. Her husband, Willett, died in 1962. (source: Money & King Funeral Home obituary, February 2012)
Willett Main Kempton
Willett Kempton was born in Mt.Carroll, Illinois in 1903, graduated from Culver Military Academy and received his Master’s degree from the University of Wisconsin. During World War II Kempton was Department Director of Information for the Office of Emergency Management, later known as the Office of War Information. From 1943 to 1945, he was in charge of radio relations for the OWI. From 1946 to 1948, he was Director of Radio for the Department of Interior, working with President Truman on radio broadcasts. Considered a pioneer in the emerging field of Communications, he became chairman of the Department of Communications, American University in 1947, until his death in 1962 (Excerpted from American University obituary, November 29th, 1962)
World War, 1939-1945 -- Women -- United States -- Correspondence.; World War, 1939-1945 -- Correspondence -- Sources; Kempton, Grace Arrington; Kempton, Grace Arrington; Kempton, Willett Main; Kempton, Willett Main; United States. Army. Women's Army Corps; United States. Office of War Information
- Mrs. W.L. Roach Incoming Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Mrs. Henry Hammond Incoming Correspondence from Grace Kempton 1937-1939 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Mrs. Henry Hammond Incoming Correspondence from Grace Kempton 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Mrs. Henry Hammond Incoming Correspondence from Grace Kempton 1943 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Mrs. Henry Hammond Incoming Correspondence from Grace Kempton Feb. - July 9, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Mrs. Henry Hammond Incoming Correspondence from Grace Kempton July 8 - Dec. 1944 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Mrs. Henry Hammond Incoming Correspondence from Grace Kempton Feb. - July 16, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Mrs. Henry Hammond Incoming Correspondence from Grace Kempton July 26 - Dec, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Mrs. Henry Hammond Incoming Correspondence from Grace Kempton Jan. - March, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Mrs. Henry Hammond Incoming Correspondence from Grace Kempton June - November 1946 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Mrs. Henry Hammond Incoming Correspondence from Grace Kempton 1948 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Mrs. Henry Hammond Incoming Correspondence from Grace Kempton 1964 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Mrs. Henry Hammond Incoming Correspondence from Grace Kempton 1960s (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Mrs. Henry Hammond Incoming Correspondence from Grace Kempton 1970 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Incoming Correspondence to Mrs. Henry Hammond 1950s (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Incoming Correspondence to Mrs. Grace Kempton 1941 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Incoming Correspondence to Mrs. Grace Kempton Jan. - Feb. 1942 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton Mar. - Aug. 1942 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Incoming Correspondence to Mrs. Grace Kempton Sept. - Dec. 1942 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Incoming Correspondence to Mrs. Grace Kempton Jan. - Mar. 1943 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Incoming Correspondence to Mrs. Grace Kempton April - June 1943 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Incoming Correspondence to Mrs. Grace Kempton July - Sept. 1943 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton Oct. - Dec. 1943 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Incoming Correspondence to Mrs. Grace Kempton Jan. - April 1944 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton May - Dec. 1944 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton 1945 (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton 1945 (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Grace Kempton Incoming Correspondence 1945 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Grace Kempton Outgoing Correspondence 1945 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton 1946 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton 1947 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton 1948 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton 1952, 1958, and 1960 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Outgoing Correspondence July 5, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton 1972 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton 1973-1978 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Mrs. Grace Kempton Incoming Correspondence from Willett Kempton 1940-1942 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Mrs. Grace Kempton Incoming Correspondence from Willett Kempton July - Nov. 10, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Mrs. Grace Kempton Incoming Correspondence from Willett Kempton Nov. 13 - Dec. 1943 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Mrs. Grace Kempton Incoming Correspondence from Willett Kempton Jan. 1944 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Mrs. Grace Kempton Incoming Correspondence from Willett Kempton May 1944 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Mrs. Grace Kempton Incoming Correspondence from Willett Kempton June 1944 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Mrs. Grace Kempton Incoming Correspondence from Willett Kempton July 1944 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Mrs. Grace Kempton Incoming Correspondence from Willett Kempton Aug. 1944 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Mrs. Grace Kempton Incoming Correspondence from Willett Kempton Sept. 1944 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Mrs. Grace Kempton Incoming Correspondence from Willett Kempton Dec. 1944 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Mrs. Grace Kempton Incoming Correspondence from Willett Kempton 1945 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Mrs. Grace Kempton Incoming Correspondence from Willett Kempton 1946 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Mrs. Grace Kempton Incoming Correspondence from Willett Kempton 1947 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Mrs. Grace Kempton Incoming Correspondence from Willett Kempton 1948 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from Willett Kempton 1993 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Mrs. Grace Kempton Incoming Correspondence from Willett Kempton undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from Mrs. Henry Hammond 1959 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from Mrs. Henry Hammond 1962 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from Mrs. Henry Hammond 1963 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from Mrs. H. B. Hammond 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from Mrs. Henry B. Hammond 1964 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from Mrs. H. B. Hammond 1965 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from Mrs. Henry B. Hammond 1967 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from Mrs. Henry B. Hammond 1968 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from Mrs. Henry B. Hammond 1969 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from Mrs. Henry B. Hammond 1970 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from Mrs. Henry B. Hammond 1971 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from Mrs. Henry B. Hammond 1972 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from Mrs. Henry B. Hammond 1973 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Mrs. Grace Kempton Incoming Correspondence from Mrs. H. B. Hammond (1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Mrs. Grace Kempton Incoming Correspondence from Mrs. H. B. Hammond (2 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from Miss Elizabeth Kempton 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from Miss Elizabeth Kempton 1964-1966 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from Miss Elizabeth Kempton 1967 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from Miss Elizabeth Kempton 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from Miss Elizabeth Kempton 1971 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from Elizabeth Kempton 1972 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from Elizabeth Kempton 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from Elizabeth Kempton 1975-1978 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from various people 1962 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton 1960-1962 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from various people 1963 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from various people 1965 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Miscellaneous Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from Col. T.A. McCrary 1963 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from Col. T.A. McCrary 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from Alice Wilson (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from Mrs. Kempton Roach 1961 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from Various people 1964 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from John E. Ladson 1969 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from G.F.H. 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from Various People 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton from Jack 1970 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous Incoming Correspondenceto Grace Kempton 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Incoming Correspondence to Willett and Grace Kempton undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton Empty Folders 1959 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton 1983-1985 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Mr. and Mrs. Kempton Incoming Correspondence 1941 - Aug. 1942 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Mr. and Mrs. Kempton Incoming Correspondence Nov. 1942 - April 1943 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Mr. and Mrs. Kempton Incoming Correspondence May 1943 - Dec. 1959 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Willett Kempton Incoming Correspondence 1938 - 1941 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Willett Kempton Incoming Correspondence 1942 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Willett Kempton Incoming Correspondence 1943 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Willett Kempton Incoming Correspondence 1944 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Willett Kempton Incoming Correspodence 1945-1948 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Willett Kempton Incoming Correspondence 1954-1960 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Willett Kempton Incoming Correspondence from Grace Kempton July 1939 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Willett Kempton Incoming Correspondence from Grace Kempton 1942 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Willett Kempton Incoming Correspondence from Grace Kempton May - June 13, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Willett Kempton Incoming Correspondence from Grace Kempton June 15 - July 15, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Willett Kempton Incoming Correspondence from Grace Kempton July 17 - Sept. 22, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Willett Kempton Incoming Correspondence from Grace Kempton 1945 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Willett Kempton Incoming Correspondence from Grace Kempton 1946-1948 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Willett Kempton Miscellaneous Incoming Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Incoming Correspondence to Willett Kempton from Annie Kempton Roach 1960s (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Incoming Correspondence to Willett Kempton from Elizabeth Kempton 1962 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Incoming Correspondence to Willett Kempton from Elizabeth Kempton 1963 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Incoming Correspondence to Willett Kempton 1939 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Incoming Correspondence to Willett Kempton 1959 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Incoming Correspondence to Willett Kempton (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Incoming Correspondence to Willett Kempton from Various People 1960 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Incoming Correspondence to Willett Kempton from Various People 1962 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Incoming Correspondence to Willett Kempton undated (Box 8, Folders 2-5)
- Incoming Correspondence to Willett Kempton 1950s (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Personal Correspondence to Willett Kempton (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Incoming Correspondence to Mrs. Grace Arrington Kempton 1951 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Incoming Correspondence to Mrs. A Kempton Roach 1950 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton 1950s (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton 1970s (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace and Willett Kempton (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Incoming Correspondence to Grace Kempton (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Incoming Correspondence to Mrs. Henry B. Hammond (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Empty Envelopes (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Outgoing Personal Correspondence from Grace Kempton to Various People 1941-1943 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Letters from Family 1941 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Correspondence to Willett Kempton from his mother (Box 8, Folder 19)
- 1950 Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 20)
- 1951 Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 21)
- 1952 Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 22)
- 1953 Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 23)
- 1954 Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 24)
- 1955 Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 25)
- 1956 Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 1)
- 1957 Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 2)
- 1958 Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 3)
- 1959 Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Personal Incoming Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 9, Folders 6-18)
- Letters to Grace Arrington from her family (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Love letters to Grace Arrington (Box 10, Folders 2-5)
- Letters from G. Kempton to her Mother (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Letter to G. Kempton from W. Kempton (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Grace Kempton Grade from W. Kempton after they were married (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Wedding Invitation for W. Kempton & G. Arrington (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Postcards (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Various Newspaper clippings (Box 10, Folders 11-12)
- Miscellaneous letters to Grace (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Article: Journalism students given advice by Veterans (Box 10, Folder 14)
- The Emory Mid-Term Dances - Grace Arrington (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Empty Envelopes - letters to Grace Arrington (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Letters for Willet Kempton (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Love Letters to Grace Arrington (Box 10, Folder 18)
- Various Photographs (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous Photograph (Box 11, Folder 2)
- General War Photos (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Photos of Cal. Westray B. Boyce (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Various Photographs (Box 11, Folders 5-6)
- WAC Photographs (Box 11, Folders 7-11)
- Various Photographs (Box 11, Folders 12-13)
- Army Life Publications (Box 11, Folders 14-17)
- WAC News Publication (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Army Life November 1944 (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Army Life (Box 11, Folder 20)
- Yank (Box 11, Folder 21)
- Yank (Box 11, Folder 22)
- Yank Vol. 3 No. 4 (Box 11, Folder 23)
- Yank Vol. 2 No. 52 (Box 11, Folder 24)
- Overseas Woman December 1945 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Yank Vol. 3 No. 22 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Yank Vol. 3 No. 21 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- WAC Newsletter (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Recruiting Conference for the Women's Army Corps (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Background Information on the Women's Army Corps, as of February 1, 1945 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Women's Place in War Women's Army Corps (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Army Service Forces Fourth Service Command Third Women's Army Corps Training Center (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Where and How WACs Live in Foreign Lands (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Interesting Items Concerning WACs Overseas (Box 12, Folder 10)
- New WAC off Duty-Dress Adds Gift Possibilities to 1944 Christmas List (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Recruiting Conference for the Women's Army Corps (Box 12, Folder 12)
- The WAC Officer A Guide to Successful Leadership (Box 12, Folder 13)
- WAC News (Box 12, Folder 14)
- The WAC Pamphlets (Box 12, Folder 15)
- WAC Newsletter Vol. 1 Numbers 2-12 (Box 12, Folder 16)
- WAC Newsletter Vol. 1 Nos. 13-16 (Box 12, Folder 17)
- WAC Newsletter Vol. 2 No. 6 - Vol. 3 No. 2 (Box 12, Folder 18)
- WAC News Publication (Box 12, Folder 19)
- WAC News Clippings (Box 12, Folder 20)
- WAC Background file-Jobs (Box 12, Folder 21)
- WAC: Relatives Armed Forces - (Reunions, Marriages etc.) (Box 12, Folder 22)
- WAC News (Box 12, Folder 23)
- WAC Background (Box 13, Folder 1)
- The Women's Army Corps (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Facts you want to know about the WAC (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Putting your Degree to work in the Womens Army Corps (Box 13, Folder 4)
- The Clipper: Local WAC's Awarded Medals for First time (Box 13, Folder 5)
- WAC stories and publications (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Air WAC: HW US strategic Air Forces in Europe (Box 13, Folder 7)
- 5203 Bivou WAC (Box 13, Folder 8)
- WACs on the Job with the Signal Corps Holabird Signal Report (Box 13, Folder 9)
- 432 WACs assigned to Manhattan Project (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Recruiting Conference for the Women's Army Corps (Box 13, Folders 11-12)
- WAC Material (Box 13, Folder 13)
- WAC Stories and Publications (Box 13, Folder 14)
- WACs Around the World (Box 13, Folder 15)
- WAC Facts (Box 13, Folder 16)
- WAC Newsletter Vol. 2 No. 10 May 1945 (Box 13, Folder 17)
- WAC Newsletter (Box 13, Folder 18)
- WAC Personal Material (Box 13, Folder 19)
- First WACs Are Welcomed to England (Box 13, Folder 20)
- WAC Personal Material (Box 13, Folder 21)
- WAC Certificate (Box 13, Folder 22)
- WAC Material (Box 13, Folders 23-24)
- WAC News (Box 13, Folder 25)
- WAC Newsletter (Box 13, Folder 26)
- Overseas Woman May 1945 (Box 13, Folder 27)
- Overseas Woman December 1945 (Box 13, Folder 28)
- Overseas Woman January 1946 (Box 13, Folder 29)
- Overseas Woman April 1945 (Box 13, Folder 30)
- Overseas Woman November 1945 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Checklist for Overseas Magazine (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Office of War Information (Box 14, Folders 3-4)
- Office of War Information Radio (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Army Information Branch, Morale Services Division (Box 14, Folders 6-7)
- The Digest Publication (Box 14, Folder 8)
- The New Yorker (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Various Clippings (Box 14, Folders 10-16)
- War Times April 20, 1945 (Box 14, Folder 17)
- Newsmap Volume IV No. 20B (Box 14, Folder 18)
- War Times Newspaper Article April 20, 1945 (Box 14, Folder 19)
- Miscellaneous Newspaper Article (Box 14, Folder 20)
- Our Town Newspaper Clippings by Grace Kempton (Box 14, Folder 21)
- The Service Woman Newspaper (Box 14, Folder 22)
- Various News Clippings (Box 14, Folder 23)
- Miscellaneous Pin (Box 14, Folder 24)
- Digest of the functions of Federal Agencies (Box 14, Folder 25)
- The United States of Armed Forces Institute (Box 14, Folder 26)
- You're on your way... Home (Box 14, Folder 27)
- How about your education (Box 14, Folder 28)
- Drafts of Press Submittals and Speeches by Grace Kempton and others (Box 15, Folders 1-12)
- U.S. Army Signal Corps Photo (Box 15, Folders 13-14)
- Grace Kempton Activities (Box 15, Folders 15-16)
- Army Times Newspaper Vol. 5 Numbers 7,9,10 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Army Times Newspaper Volume 5 Numbers 12,15,41 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Army Times Newspaper Volume 6 Number 7 (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Various Clippings (Box 16, Folders 4-9)
- Yank: The Army Weekly - Jan. 5 Vol. 3 No. 29 1945 (Box 16, Folder 10)
- Yank: The Army Weekly - Dec. 1 Vol. 3 No. 24 1944 (Box 16, Folder 11)
- Yank: The Army Weekly - Jan. 12 Vol 3 No. 30 1945 (Box 16, Folder 12)
- Yank: The Army Weekly - March 9 Vol. 3 No. 38 1945 (Box 16, Folder 13)
- Miscellaneous Material (Box 16, Folders 14-15)
- Office of War information (Box 16, Folder 16)
- Speech for WAAC Service Command Director Westray Boyce (Box 16, Folder 17)
- Public Relations Branch (Box 16, Folder 18)
- Notes (Box 16, Folder 19)
- Allied Insignia (Box 17, Folder 1)
- GI Bill of Rights (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Digest Publication (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Memorandum for the Commanding General, Army Service Forces (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Background for War Time Magazine 1939 (Box 17, Folder 5)